DUNCAN J. MAYER

DATA SCIENTIST

DuncanMayer77@gmail.com · Personal Website · Github · LinkedIn

SUMMARY

I am a data scientist with nearly a decade of experience using data to predict and understand complex behavior and phenomenon. I maintain good coding practices and am comfortable building, evaluating, and interpreting everything from well known algorithms to be spoke models. In addition to my methodological work, I bring domain expertise in organizational theory and have published articles on nonprofit finance, data use, and neighborhood effects.

PROGRAMMING: R (8 years) | SQL (4 years) | Stan (3 years) | Python (1 year)

STATISTICS: Hierarchical Models | Spatial Statistics | Longitudinal Data Analysis | Machine Learning | Experimentation

EDUCATION

Case Western Reserve University

Cleveland, OH (Expected Spring) 2023

PhD in Social Welfare

Marywood University Scranton, PA Masters of Social Work 2017 Bachelors of Social Work 2015

RECENT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BeVera Solutions Atlanta, GA Statistician Sept. 2022-Present

• Led all statistical aspects of 3 white papers for the National Center for Immunization and Respiratory Diseases evaluating the nation's COVID response (R, SQL)

• Automated data quality reports, reducing missing data by 10 percent (SQL, R)

Case Western Reserve University

Cleveland, OH

Data Scientist

Aug. 2018-Aug. 2022

- Led all aspects of N scientific studies, publishing multiple first author papers including novel methodologies and state of the art applications (R, SQL, Stan)
- · Communicated methods and insights in over 5 technical talks at scientific conferences and over 150 hours of course lectures
- Co-authored 3 funded research papers paring survey and administrative data
- Developed programming courses for the data science for social good certificate

The Institute for Public Policy and Economic **Development**

Wilkes-Barre, PA

July 2017-June 2018

Research Analyst

- · Co-authored 11 funded research papers on topics relevant to state government, leading data analysis in 5 (R)
- Provided adhoc data analysis to a variety government and corporate stakeholders

SELECT PAPERS

Simmer Down Now! A Study of Revenue Volatility and Dissolution in Nonprofit Organizations

• Quantified the effect of revenue volatility on dissolution in nonprofit organizations using archival tax records organizations (N = 2,126,894) and discrete time survival models (R, SQL)

Can a Measurement Error Perspective Improve Estimation in Neighborhood Effects Research? A Hierarchical Bayesian Methodology

• Developed a probabilistic model to incorporate sampling error into neighborhoods effects research using a full Bayesian Methodology (Stan, R)

Understanding Location and Density: A Spatial Analysis of Cuyahoga County's Nonprofit Sector

• Quantified the effects of location of nonprofit revenue using penalized spines (generalized additive models) showing the "best" locations tend to central in agglomeration clusters (R)